If you've ever been to the store and bought
these kind of things you'll know that the
majority of the time they look like this......
smashed to bits, tiny, pretty uneventful.
Well if you want to know how to make
perfect ones and chocolate versions too,
which is what we're going to do today,
stick around and I'll show you how to do it
[Music] yep in today's video we're
going to do chocolate waffle cones,
sugar cones they're sometimes called, as well
they're really easy to make, you don't need.... I
mean I've got a waffle press but you don't need
one of those, you can just buy one of these,
they're like $22 Canadian Dollar on Amazon. Dirt
cheap and you use it on the hob, same kind of
thing, same recipe and a lot more fun to make than
poping into Walmart and buying their crappy ones.
So let's get on with it, what do we need?
outcome the scales, you kind of want to be
pretty accurate on this. I will calculate cup
measurements for those people that need them.
But nice and simple, all purpose
flour 80g, and on top of that 20g
of cocoa powder giradelli, use a
good one. Into that 50g of sugar.
That's our dry ingredients, let's just
combine them up we're doing that just to
break up any lumps of cocoa powder and
flour that are there in here we've got
140g of water and we're going to add 20g
of olive oil and into that 20g of refined
coconut oil. Refined because I don't want
it to taste of coconut. We're going to need
to melt this one in the microwave just for a
few seconds so let's do that.... 20g [Music]
we're going to put our melted coconut oil
into our water, give that a bit of a stir.
Dry ingredients... wet ingredients....
whisk to combine the two and whisk it up
and what you'll be left with is
something that looks like this.
It's actually a similar consistency to an
ice cream base, maybe a thick ice cream
base. So now that that's ready this needs
to go into the fridge for at least an hour
to make sure that flour is fully hydrated and
allows the mixture to relax so let's do that.
So whatever waffle iron you've got, get it
out if it's a really nice one like this then
get it turned on heating up to 180 C
which is 350 F if you're using one on
the hob then get your thermometer laser
thermometer out and get it warming up.
So the essential things we're going to need here
is some way to get our batter on, I've got one
of these, they used to be called ice cream scoops
and now I think they're called cookie scoops but
this is a 1/4 cup measurement so 60g-65g. You want
that amount on an 8 in waffle cone iron this that
is 8 in across so you get a really decent size.
Most waffle irons will come with something like
this which is a molded plastic former you can
also buy something like this you can't buy this
one this is this is mine I made this 3D printed
this you can buy stainless steel ones online
they're about $150 seems a lot of money to me you
can use whatever use paper you know make a cone
out of it and shape into that use whatever you've
got to hand but whilst we wait for this to heat
up let's just talk about one thing that's really
essential with our waffle batter in the fridge
this is actually like 2 days after I started this
video you need it in the fridge to firm up you
don't want a runny batter you need to be able to
scoop it in some semi viscous form you don't want
it running onto the top otherwise your waffle cone
is going to be too thin so you need that batter to
be nice and thick so that this lid doesn't squash
it too thin because it it's too delicate then you
can't reasonably hold on to it or bite it because
it would just crumble in your hands so thick
okay almost like soft serve ice cream something
along that kind of consistency that's what you're
trying to get okay we're a couple of minutes
away so I'll cut back once we're ready to start
dosing [Music] up right I got a little fan over
there cuz I've got a smoke alarm right above me
and this will smoke a little bit when you put
it in you got a couple of choices spray oil
olive oil whatever doesn't matter what you use
if you want to oil this then I normally just put
a little bit of olive oil on there and just
wipe it over nice and quick that's more than
enough in a commercial environment you would
definitely use your spray oil just spray it one
on each surface and you're good to go but we're
ready our light is off our waffle iron is up to
temperature let's get some in as you can see like
it's a very thick batter okay nice scoop straight
on there we go 1 minute 25
[Music] seconds there we go 125 what we
need something just to help us take it out
like so and nice and quick get your roller
and roll it into shape like so okay you don't
need.... I mean, I got asbestos hands so I don't
recommend you do that but essentially all you're
doing is you're holding it into shape until
it cools down enough to keep it's shape okay.
In a commercial environment, you have
your form you would roll it and then
put it straight in the stand we are good to
go chocolate waffle cone I'm going to stand
that in that cup that is a glass whilst it's
still mildly soft you can just pop it in the
fridge no more than about
30 seconds but what we can
do let make another chocolate waffle cone you
got a couple of options um for the for the bottom
um you find a lot of the ice cream parlors will
drop chocolate into there where we'll drop a
little mini marshmallow into there you know
all these kind of things as long as you wait
until it's cool before you do that no problems
at all otherwise just learn how to close the
ends off it's uh it's not overly difficult you
just have to make sure you fold the tip get that
just shy of the edge of your circle so that
when you roll it that very last bit of your
disc rolls in on itself all right chocolate
waffle cone only one thing left to do...
Chocolate waffle cones, not as difficult as people
lead you to believe but hey.... decadent flavor,
I used a high quality cocoa powder in this,
use whatever you got available but the better
the ingredient the better the flavor...
it's crispy as you can hear, tastes delicious
easy to make. You don't need expensive gear
like I said, $22 on Amazon they normally come
with this if not these are like $3 or $4 that
is enough to get you homemade waffle cones.
Temperature 180°C/ 350°F for 1 minute 25 seconds
you can probably extend that to about 1 minute
50 seconds somewhere in that range any more than
that and you're going to start burning it hope you
enjoyed this video I've got some affiliate links
for this waffle iron down in the description
really nice one, surprisingly cheap as well
if you make a lot of ice cream and you got
kids my kid loves this she always wants an
ice cream cone the ones you buy from the store
as you seen they're crap they break these ones
perfect anyway thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like subscribe see you next time
[Music]